能打擾一下大家嗎?
Can I get everyone's attention?
威廉姆斯先生 請起立
Mr. Williams please rise.
請舉起你的右手
Please raise your right hand sir.
你能莊嚴的宣誓 你說陳述的證據都是真實的嗎?
Do you solemnly swear that the testimony you about to give is the truth.
完全真實 沒有半點假話麼?
the whole truth and nothing but the truth.So help you God.
-是的 我發誓 -謝謝 請坐
- Yes sir. - Thank you sir. You be seated.
威廉姆斯先生 你能告我們在深海處
Mr. Williams can you please give us your best
到底發生了什麼嗎?
recollection of the event on the Deepwater Horizon?
九點左右的時候 我正在和我的妻子通話
I was on the phone around 9:30 with my wife.
我聽到了呲呲的響聲
That's when I heard the hissing noise.
我聽到了引擎故障的聲音
I heard the engines start to rave.
呲呲的響聲變成了轟鳴聲
The hissing turn into a full blown roar.
聲音大的我無法形容
Higher than I can even describe it.
幾秒鐘後 就發生了巨大的爆炸
And within second there's a huge explosion.
殘片飛的到處都是
Projectiles coming from everywhere.
熱浪熱的受不了
The heat was overwhelming.
你能解釋下報警系統是什麼設置的嗎?
Can you please tell me how the Deepwater Horizon alarm system is set up.
警報系統是用來通知整個平台的
The general alarm is set up to inform the entire rig of
第一是火災警報 第二是可燃氣體警報
Number one fire number two combustible gas.
第三是毒氣警報
Number three toxic gas.
每一種的警報聲和警示燈都不一樣
Each condition has a distinct tone and a distinct visual light.
在4月20日的晚上
On the eve of April 20th
你是否聽到了警報聲?
Did you hear anyone of those alarm on Deepwater Horizon?
沒有 先生
No sir.
你知道為什麼你沒有聽到警報嗎?
Do you know why you never heard that alarm?
威廉姆斯先生?
Mr. William?
深海浩劫
DEEP HORIZON
水下三千英尺
Passing 3000 feet.
繼續下潛
Continuing down.
保持在管道北側
Need to stick to the north side far east.
進行掃瞄
Scan on it.
還有大約500米的管道待檢
About 500 foot rising up.
看到防噴器了
BOP is in the view.
防噴器
Blowout Preventer (BOP)
油井壓力控制和故障防護裝置
PRESSURE WELL CONTROL AND RISK FAILURE
孔深3.5千米
Drilling depth 5.6 kilometers.
現在井口怎麼樣?
How's that wellhead service working?
輕微腐蝕 跟我想像的差不多
Minor corrosion not much more than I expected of. Well ahead of it's age.
搞定 讓回來吧.
Allright working. Crank it up.
我剛做了個很瘋狂的夢
I just had the craziest dream.
喔 喔 堶惘釦睇?
Wow...wow was I in it?
我在..一場音樂會上
I was no...I was at a concert.
舞台旁邊有兩隻
and then on the side of the stage there was this
兩條腿的兔子
two-legged rabbit.
這有什麼可怕的
I don't want no part of it. I want tap out.
聽我說
Listen to me.
我一動
I would moved.
它就跟著我動
and then he would mimic everthing I was doing.
別說了 我知道接下來會發生什麼
Don't tell me anymore because I know where this is going.
- 我認為這兔子是我媽媽 -媽媽 是的 我知道
- You think the rabbit was my mother. - Mother. Yes I know.
多虧了你 這下我也要做噩夢了
I think it was my worst nightmare.Thank you.
- 這沒道理 - 好
- It was hostile. - Ok.
- 這是某種預兆 - 我知道了
- It was a hostile rabbit. - I got it.
你要幹什麼?
I'm sorry. What are you doing?
就這樣 你就要離開我21天?
That it? That's how you going to leave me for 21 day's next.
我會和你一起睡
I want you get your sleep.
我想你和你做其他的事情
Well I need other things beside sleep.
那你得保證不再提你的媽媽
You have to promise not to bring your mother then.
*笑聲*
Hmmm
你想要30秒?
So you want the thirty?
60秒?
The sixty?
還是90秒的套餐?
Or the ninety seconds package?
我要一整個90秒的套餐.
I'm going to take the whole ninety.
這壓力山大啊 壓力好大.
Pressure. Pressure. Pressure.
我會想念你這笑容
I gonna miss that laugh.
- 還有這嘴唇
- That mouth.
讓我看看你的眼睛
Give me those eyes.
我愛你
I love you.
我們不是這樣約定的.
This is not our deal dude.
好了 好了
Allright. Allright.
你看 你總是高估你的修理技術.
You can see you obviously overestimating your skills as a mechanic.
你說什麼?
What was that?
走吧 寶貝
Let's go baby.
- 我來開
- Let me drive. - Uh uh.
- 我來開 - 不
- Let me drive. - Nope.
拜託啦
Pretty please.
- 你真想開麼?- 當然
- You really want to drive? - Yeah.
那把你的車賣了 買一輛吧
Then sell that piece of shit and get a Ducatti.
喔 厲害.
Wow. Builder not trying to shop.
我之所以沒敲門 是因為我還想要個弟弟
I only didn't not knock because I want a brother.
行 真煩
Okay. That's disturbing.
你確實什麼都不知道
You're not supposed to know anything about that.
你只知道小孩可愛
You're supposed to just think babies are cute.
- 請你坐下 - 我真的想要個弟弟
- Will you sit down please? - Really I want a brother.
做的怎麼樣了?
How's it going?
- 親愛的 給你爸爸看看 - 我還沒做好
- Honey show daddy. - I'm not done yet.
- 你做的很不錯 -展示一下
- You did such a good job. - It's showtime.
那確實很不錯
It's really great.
別盯著我看
You can't look at me.
為什麼?-因為那讓我覺得不舒服
- Why? - Because it makes me feel uncomfortable.
- 我看著你會讓你不舒服?
- Am i looking at you makes you uncomfortable?
別看著我 我的爸爸叫麥克
Stop. My dad is Mike.
他在一個石油鑽井平台工作
He works in a drilling rig that pumps oil out from underneath the ocean.
不對 我們並不抽石油 我們是探索者
No no the Deepwater doesn't pump a drop of oil okay. We're the explorers.
爸爸和他的朋友們尋找石油
So my dad and his friend finds the oil
然後插入管道等古板的隊員過來
and then puts it in all the plumbing so other lamer cruise can come in
- 不許亂用詞彙 - 他們就是古板
- Don't say lamer - They're lamer.
古板的隊員什麼都不用做
Okay listen even those lamer dudes they don't have to pump anything remember.
因為石油會自己噴出來.
Because the oil comes rushing out at you.
- 行 行 行 -好的 好的 好的
- No no no - Allright allright allright.
因為石油是個怪獸
Because that oil is a monster.
就像那些又大又老的恐龍一樣
Like the mean old dinosaur all that oil used to be.
所以3億年來
So for 300 million years ...
這些恐龍生活的地方越來越小 越來越小
these old dinosaurs have been getting squeeze tighter and tighter tighter
我們懂 沒必要重複那麼多次
We get it. Just use two tighter.
因為廣闊的海洋環繞著這點點陸地
Cause they got a miles of earth and ocean pressing down on them.
他們被困在陸地上
They are trapped under it.
所以爸爸和他的朋友們在地上打了個洞
So Dad and his friends make a hole on their roof.
是的
Yeah!
那些又大又老的恐龍才不會信這個的
And these mean old dinosaurs can't believe it.
所以他們涌進洞 然後 砰
So they rush to the new hole. Then smack.
撞到一個大機器 那是爸爸和朋友們
They ran into a big machine that he and his friends pump down
放在海底的 叫做
from the ocean floor called
- 大個子防護罩? - 防噴器
- Big guy preventer? - Blowout preventer.
然後他們撞上了一團泥漿
They run into this stuff called mud.
- 對 把它放這兒 他們困在了泥漿
- Allright get it in there.But they cramp on the straw.
泥漿又粘又稠 把它們關在了那.
The mud is so thick and heavy it blocks the monster from coming out.
然後他們航行到另一個地方.
And then they sail away to the next.
然後那些差勁的隊員再次出現 又做同樣的事情
That's when all the lame-o showed up all happy like they did something.
不准說"差勁"
Don't say lame-o.
但是其實是爸爸征服得恐龍
But it was my daddy who tamed the dinosaurs.
- 對! - 是的
- Yeah! - Yeah.
太令人驚嘆了-要是你永遠十歲多好
That was amazing. Stay 10 forever please.
爸爸 你得送我一塊化石
Daddy you need to get me a fossil.
行
I will.
我要舉著它說 是我的爸爸打敗了那些恐龍
I want to be able to put it up and say my daddy tamed the dinosaurs.
告訴他麥琪的爸爸做了什麼
Tell daddy what Maggie's dad did.
他的爸爸在動物園工作 給她帶了一隻企鵝回來
Her dad works at the zoo and he brought a real penguin.
怎麼能這樣!
You can't do that!
- 他帶回了一次企鵝 -什麼東西能和真的企鵝比?
- He brought a penguin. - How do you compete with a penguin?
- 那你帶回來一塊化石 - 那肯定違規了
- You get a fossil.- There should be rules.
我的天吶
Oh my God.
怎麼了?
What?
- 罐子婺侉﹞F - 快讓它停下來
- The hole is so much for the can. - Stop it!
讓它停下來
Calm it.
加油 上班
Buy gas go to work ...
再加油 上班
Buy gas back to work.
買更多的油去上班
Buy more gas get to work.
你知道密碼是多少麼?
Hey you know the password right with all the insurance stuff agent and all.
- 有事找舒曼律師- 你說什麼?
- Call Schuman first. - What are you talking about? - I just...
- 你在擔心什麼?- 上次坐飛機我被嚇到了.
- What are you on about?
- I just got spook on going home on a chopper last August.
給我一點
Give me some of that.
親愛的 當水手不在抱怨的時候 你就該擔心了
Babe the only time you start worrying about a marine is when he stops bitching.
- 不許用我的話反駁我-我就要用你話反駁你
- Don't use my line against me. - I'm using your line against you.
- 別那樣做 -我已經做了
- Don't use my line. - I just did.
- 好了 抱歉 - 好的
-Allright bread. -Allright fish.
- 三周後見
- See you in three weeks.
好好的
Behave.
下一個
Next.
-早上好 傑米先生-你還好麼?薩拉
- Good morning Mr. Jimmy. - How are we doing Sarah?
- 還不錯 你了?-一切都好
- Good how are you doing? - All yeah.
把你的包放在指示標誌上
You can place you bag on the baggage scale up and step on your feet.
- 今天去哪兒?-老地方 深海平台
- Where you heading today? - Same place. Deepwater Horizon.
- 去哪兒? - 深海平台
- Where you flying to? - Deepwater Horizon.
- 你做什麼工作麼? -翻譯
- And who you work for? - Transocean.
- 想知道你的體重麼?-是的
- Want to know how much you weigh? - You know I do.
- 181
- 我怎麼說的來著?-還不錯 繼續保持
- What I tell you?.- You did good. Keep it that way.
- 好了 先坐一下 等航班到了
- All ready have a seat in the lobby and we'll
我們會通知你的- 謝謝
call you when your flight is ready. - Thank you.
西姆斯先生 奧布萊恩先生
Mr. Sims. Mr. O'Bryan.
戴維德 西姆斯
David Sims.
吉米 哈勒 深水平台的裝設主管
Jimmy Harrell. Officer Installation Manager on Deepwater.
很高興能帶我們出來
Thank you very much for taking us out today.
我知道你們都很忙 不該麻煩你的
I know you guys are swamp. You didn't have to.
應該的
I had to.
不介意的話能把那領帶解下來麼?
Listen you mind losing that tie?
行
I would.
不是因為領帶本身 是它的顏色
It's not the tie. It is the color.
紫色?
Purple?
更像是紫紅色
More magenta.
為什麼了?
and?
紫紅色警報是提醒鑽丼台出了嚴重問題.
Well magenta alarm on oil rig is as bad as it gets.
還是迷信點好
As worthy as superstitions.
- 名字? - 麥克 威廉姆斯
- Name? - Mike Williams.
- 今天去哪兒? -深海平台
- Where you heading today? - Deepwater Horizon.
你閒的時候幹什麼?
What you do in your downtime?
-我又開始玩汽艇了 -是嗎?
- Ahh start working on that boat again. - Yeah?
我正準備從600提速到1200
I'm upping it to 600 horsepower 1 200 horsepower.
而且我還得到了一個森塞尼奇螺旋槳;
And I got me a Sensenich propeller.
- 你想讓它飛起來麼? -不 我只是想更快
- You trying to make it fly? - No I just want it to go faster.
- 明白? - 收到 全體乘客都已登機
- Clear? - Roger I got everyone.
報告 我已經在飛行系統中鎖定目標-深海平台
Boscow I got Deepwater Horizon coordinate in the FMS.
492 機尾已準備好 風速平緩
492 you tail is clear. Wind is calm
巴黎控制塔 布里斯托2報告
Paris control this is Bristow 2 Bravo Go.
我們正飛往公海
We heading to open ocean.
預計45分鐘後到達深海平台
ETA 45 minutes to Deepwater Horizon.
收到 布里斯托2
Roger that Bristow 2 Bravo Go.
你在英國石油公司是幹什麼的?
What is it that you do at BP Mr. Sims?
- 管理 -哦 該死 我們完了
- Complacent. - Oh shit here we go Jimmy.
你知道 我們的進度有點落後
Well as you know we a little behind.
43天 誰又會去算了?
43 days. But who's counting right?
-想好怎麼花你的獎金了麼? - 修個游泳池
- What are you gonna do with your bonus Mike? - Dig a pool.
- 你呢? -修我的車
- You? - Fix my car.
一號井崩塌的時候
You do know the first well collapse on us?
花了五天時間搶救 用了一個價值100萬美元的鑽桿
Took us five days just to pull a million-dollar drill pipe.
- 這能怪誰呢? -你開的什麼車?
- Whose fault was that? - You driving this how much it worth?
- 69年野馬 -快背式?
- 69 Mustang. - Flash by?
- 塑料頂 -什麼故障?
- Vinyl top. - What's up with it?
發動機問題 開起來都是汽油味
Today was a rough vital I mean the exhaust smell like gas right out of a pump.
- 熄火時有麼? -沒有 油箱沒有漏
- Smell gas but it's not over ? - No. So it's not a leak in the tank.
喔喔
Owww!!!
剛剛撞到了一隻鳥
That was bird strike folks.
我們什麼也不會說的
I'm ain't saying nothing.
距離深海平台還有1.6千米
Deepwater Horizon is only a mile out.
我們會安全著陸的
We should be fine to land.
然後會進行安全檢查
We'll run a safety check there.
我們會安全著陸的
We should be fine to land.
然後會進行安全檢查
We'll run a safety check there.
這麼宏偉的東西只有上帝才能創造出來
If anything that big ought to be made by God.
太漂亮了 -而且水下沒有任何支撐
That's beautiful. - You know it's not on a stilt it's not jackup.
是啊 只是我還是不敢想想它只是一艘船
Yeah that too and still can't believe that thing is a boat.
那你要謝謝後面這位年輕的女士
You know who you can thank to is a very talented young lady right back here.
供應船班克斯敦號停這兒做什麼
What the hell does Bankston doing here?
誰下的命令?
Who gave him that order?
布里斯托請求降落
2 Bravo Gulf permission to land.
深海平台
DEEPWATER HORIZON
半潛式海上石油鑽丼平台
OFFSHORE DRILLING semisubmersible
距離路易斯安那州東南海岸42英里
65 KM SOUTHEAST COAST OF LOUISIANA
距海底高度5200英尺
FREE FLOATING 1 585 M ON OCEAN FLOOR
平台工作人員126名
126 WORKERS ON BOARD
歡迎登船
Welcome aboard!
你們已經完工了麼?
You guys already done?
我不知道該什麼說.吉米先生
I don't know what to tell you Mr. Jimmy.
它們完工了麼? - 我不知道該什麼說
- Hey you guys finished? - I don't know what to tell you.
- 誰去和衛德林談談 -什麼?你們完工了?
- Someone got to talk to Vidrine. - What? Are you finished?
- 嘿 斯科普先生 - 你好 先生
- Hey Skip. - Yes sir.
- 倫敦的隊伍已經撤了 - 是的 斯倫貝謝也走了
- The recording equipment already going? - Yes Schlumberger is outside.
得保證底下已經牢固了
It was supposed to prove in concrete down there.
- 他們已經完事兒了 - 麥克 你好嗎
- They already finished? - Mike how are you?
斯科普 完事兒了
Skip we're done?
- 你得跟維德林談談 - 和維德林?
- You have to talk to Vidrine. - With Vidrine?
- 他說了些啥 - 啥也沒聽見
- What did he say? - I hear nothing.
斯科普都說了些什麼
What Skip said?
他們應該測試海床上混凝土的強度的
Should verify the cement bond.
我覺得他們沒做就跑了
I think they left without doing so.
什麼?
What? Do not you ...?
- 公司讓那些人回家了 - 真的假的
- Schlumberger BP sent home. - Seriously?
是的
Yes.
庫赫塔 為啥班克斯敦號停在這兒
Kuchta what does the Bankston here?
- 也不打個招呼 - 班克斯敦號在這幹嘛
- Good day to you too. - What does Bankston here?
早上好 皮特
Good morning Pete.
見到我高興不
Happy to see me?
見到你總是很開心 安德莉亞
I am always glad to see you Andrea.
衛生間在哪 威廉姆斯
Where is the bathroom Williams?
牌子上寫著「廁所」那
Sign that says toilet.
- 斯科普有說啥關於水泥測試的嗎 - 他沒告訴我
- Skip saying anything to you about running the cement log? - He didn't call me.
我們這是徹底完事了還是咋了
We're in a war here and I'm just now finding out about it?
他們怎麼有時間做水泥測試呢 這就飛走了
Cause I'm sure don't know how they have the time to do a cement test cause they're flying away.
- 我也就是把船放下去而已 - 壓力測試結果如何
- Shit Jimmy i just drive the boat man. - How that positive test go?
結果不錯 我們正在拆卸裝置
Positive test clear. We're in rig down mode.
- 拆卸裝置 -情況怎麼樣
- Rig down mode - How are we looking?
靜止166度 風向185度 風速5公里每小時
A 166 degrees. Winds 185 degrees at 5 knots.
海況不錯
The sea is calm as good.
正在有效區域中央
Right in the middle of the permitted area.
還在跟那個騎摩托的約會嗎
Are you still dating that itsy bitsy guy with the motorcycle?
- 推進器有任何問題嗎 - 安德莉亞
- Any issue with the thruster? - Andrea.
是的 先生
Yes sir?
呼叫班克斯敦號上的蘭德瑞船長 問問他們在幹什麼
Get on radio with Captain Landry on Bankston see what he's doing and why.
好的 吉米先生
You got it Mr. Jimmy.
呼叫班克斯敦號 這堿O地平線號 完畢
Damon Bankston this is Deepwater Horizon over.
地平線號 這堿O班克斯敦號 請繼續
Deepwater Horizon here Damon Bankston go ahead.
頭想知道你們在這幹嘛
Damon I wants to know what you doing here.
我們就快離開這個大怪獸了
Over here we're getting off this beast and moving on to the next.
你可以管它叫婊子... 什麼時候撤
You can call it a bitch. When are we supposed to be leaving?
上面通知我說18:00開始壓注泥漿
Well I'm told to be ready to start taking on drilling mud about 18:00
哇哦
Wow.
聽說早上進行了正壓力試驗
I heard about the positive pressure test this morning.
我猜他們認為負壓力測試也會正常
They guess the negative test is going to run just as smooth.
-他們告訴我準備好離開 - 他們是誰
- They told me to get ready to start moving on. - Who's they?
石油公司的人 我也不清楚
BP company men. Vidrine Kaluza.
我正在等命令去收集你們的泥漿 還有問題嗎
I wait for the order and come pick up your mud. Any other question?
沒了 就這樣
No that's it.
石油公司的人認為我們已經調試好這條"猛獸"
So BP company men Vidrine and Kaluza are hoping that we have tamed this bitch
並且在18:00進行泥漿壓注 對嗎 船長
and are ready to displace drilling mud at 1800 hours is that correct Captain?
是這樣的 早上好 吉米先生
That is correct. Morning Mr. Jimmy.
真沒想到 就這樣
All the sudden. Just like that.
謝謝你 船長
Thank you Captain.
該死的電話還是不工作 麥克
And the goddamn phone still don't work Mike.
我可是跟你一條線上的
Hey I flew with you Mr. Jimmy.
幫我個忙 去下面找到傑森問問
Can you do me a favor run down to the drill shack
斯倫貝謝的人有沒有做好水泥測試
And ask Jason if those Schlumberger guys did their job. If they run the cement log.
這就去
Roger that.
謝謝
Thank you.
先生們 你們能告訴我寫水泥測試的情況嗎
Gentlemen you couldn't perhaps enlighten me on the cement log situation could you?
水泥測試
Cement log?
他們怎麼計劃的 怎麼進行的 到底有沒有做
You know if they're planning it? Running it? Did it?
恩
Yeah?
不太清楚 嘿 羅尼
Not really. Hey Ronnie.
你的野馬可能是點火方面的問題
Might be the ignition problem on your Mustang.
我想可能是火花塞的問題
I'm seeing it maybe failed plug.
也可能是某根線或者分油器
Could be a wire. Could be distributer.
- 聽起來有沒有跳杠 -沒有
- Does it sounds like it skipping? - No.
我在想這些值錢的設備是不是都壞了
You know what I'm going to do for you young lady? You keep
- 謝謝啊 - 聽著
- Geez thanks. - Hey...
手動還是自動
Stickshift or automatic?
你知道我的
Do you know me?
換擋得悠著點
Oh you gonna start grinding shit out of that clutch I know that.
- 是嘛 豐田先生 -恩
- Oh yeah says Mr. Toyota. - Aha.
平台人員請注意 安全通知
Attention all rig.
設備來了
Moving equipment.
過來 寶貝 過來寶貝
Come to me baby. Come to me baby. Come on.
停
Cancel.
抽400桶泥漿
Three four hundred barrels mud.
收到 開始執行
Roger that. Beginning actuation.
安裝鑽油管好有趣 非常有趣
Insert drill pipe is very funny very funny.
閉嘴
Shut up.
嘿 唐老鴨
Hey. Duck!
啥事兒 麥克
What up Mike?
- 你怎麼樣 凱勒布 - 嘿 麥克
- How are you doing Caleb? - Hey Mike how you doing man?
- 幾個鐘頭前還可以 - 為什麼?
- It's a lot better couple of hours ago. - Why is that?
因為那時我在睡覺
I was asleep.
恩
Yes?
我們都被叫起來一直加班
Yeah. We all got woken up guys got us working over.
如果我們想晚上走的話 還得安裝不少管子
Got a lot of pipes to pull for if we want to get out of here at night.
日常著裝 看起來挺美啊
What's up with the street clothes? You look pretty.
傑米挺火大 他想知道水泥測試的情況
Aw man Mr. Jimmy is pissed he wants to know if we got some of that cement bond log test.
不太確定 我想沒有
I'm not sure. I don't think so.
沒有 嘿 肖恩！ - 恩
-No? Hey Shane! - Yeah?
過來 斯倫貝謝進行水泥測試了嗎
Come here buddy. Schlumberger run a cement bond log test?
不知道 我覺得他們沒做 我才起來
I do not know. I don't think they did it. I just woke up so ...
- 你是蠢嗎 -蠢不蠢不知道
- Aren't that stupid? - I don't know if it's stupid ...
但肯定不聰明
but it ain't smart.
瞧 同步小王子們
Look at what you guys like synchronized swimmers.
你要是用腦過度 他會頭疼的
I think if you think too much you going to give him a headache.
- 忙去吧 - 好的
- Piped down. - Yes.
往上 上
Up up.
- 我看著了 - 大家好
- I care workers. - Hello.
你這穿的是啥
What the hell are you wearing?
吉米想知道斯倫貝謝有沒有做過水泥測試
Mr. Jimmy wants to know if the Schlumbeger run the cement bond log test.
- 什麼 -水泥測試幫幫忙唄
- The what? - Cement job. Test the cement job. Come on man work with me.
- 誰 -別扯了 吉米急著呢
- Who that again? - Cut the shit man come on Jimmy's piss man.
- 斯倫貝謝 你個二貨 - 他們進行測試了嗎
- Schlumberger you democrat. - Did they run the test?
沒有 維德林和卡魯扎直接讓他們回去了
No Vidrine and Kaluza sent them home without testing anything.
- 為什麼他們要這樣做 - 他們也沒跟我說 麥克
- Why the hell would they do that? - I don't feel the urge to take me through their thinking Mike.
我覺得吧 就是
But I assume it got something to do with...
省錢 省錢 省錢
Money money money money
省錢！
Money!
電話已經壞了
The phone is broken.
該死的
Shit.
嗨 吉米先生
Hey Mr. Jimmy.
說
Go Ahead.
石油公司讓那些人回家了 啥測試也沒做
That BP sent the Schlumberger team home without running any test.
沒進行水泥測試
There was no cement bond log.
謝了 麥克
Thank you Mike.
麥克 工作站A死機了
Mike the "A" chair just crash.
- 該死的 -又藍屏了
- Dammit. - Blue screen of death again.
嗨 唐老鴨 你的工作站還工作嗎
Hey Duck is that chair still up?
不太穩定 而且我這的煙霧報警失效了
My computer screen is shaky and my smoke detector's out.
你那怎麼樣 麥克
How you doing Mike?
該死
Shit.
我去拿工具回來修
I double back and grab my tools and I'll be back to fix it.
用邦迪和口香糖麼
Doing it all with band-aids and bubble gum my man.
每次我想成立個樂隊 這都能找到3、4個人
Every time I peel off a band-aid this on this rig i will find three or four more.
不行啊
Spitting glue ain't getting it done.
「省錢」那段 來吧
One more time with the money. Come on.
- 你們都練了這麼久了 - 省錢 省錢 省錢
- You've been rehearsing for weeks. - Money money...
不是 高潮那段
Nah nah the good part man.
這就是高潮了！省錢！
That is the good part.
死了也值了 全能的美元啊
It could kill for that money. The almighty dollar.
你好啊 好萊塢
Hello Hollywood.
- 麥克！ - 什麼事 戴爾
- Mike! - What's the word Dale ?!
- 我們已經完事了嗎 我也不清楚 可能吧
- What do you know? We done? - Not much. Could be.
好吧 今晚我打算釣魚
Yeah I am going fishing tonight. Undercover.
今晚可能開始正式幹活了 沒時間釣魚了
I got a feeling we're not getting off this well tonight I think nobody is going to be doing no fishing.
你要用你的吊車嗎 釣個鯨魚啥的
You going to use your crane man? Maybe catch a beluga or shamu?
好主意
Good idea.
該死 我打賭下一次我們還會在同一個位置
Shit. Willing to make a bet we'll hit the same spot next hitch.
- 賠率呢 - 50比1
- Yeah give me odds? - 50 to one.
不賭了
Ahh shit. I ain't touching that.
30比1 同一個位置
30 to one. Same spot.
沒可能
No way.
麥克 威廉姆斯 你個小氣鬼！
Mike Williams you cheap bastard.
- 帕崔克- 怎麼樣 麥克
- Patrick. - What's going on Mike?
- 你聽說了什麼 - 據說我們已經準備好了
- What's the word? - I heard we done.
- 準備好了 -恩
-We're done? - Yeah.
- 誰說的 -我不能告訴你
- Who you heard that from? - I can't tell you all that much.
什麼叫你不能告訴我
What do you mean you can't tell me that?
- 就是不行- 為什麼?
- I just can't tell you. - Why can't you tell me that?
我不能說 不過我能告訴你戈登正在找你
I can not tell you. But I can tell you that Gordon is looking for you.
-戈登告訴你完工了 -不是不是
- Did Gordon tell you that? - No he didn't tell me that.
- 他要幹嘛 -我也不清楚 好像要給你看什麼東西
- What going on then? - I dont know. He got something to show you.
- 你知道些啥 - 我們準備好了
- What do you know? - I know we're done.
你去我工作間了
Are you on my shop?
- 沒 - 不准碰我的東西
- No. - Don't touch my shit.
- 我沒碰你東西 - 趕緊去工作
- I wasn't touching your shit - Go fix something.
- 早上好 麥克- 你也是 該死
- Have a good day Mike. - You too. Shit.
等下 親愛的
Wait babe hold on.
你剛才說什麼
What were you saying?
好消息 直升機沒有墜毀
Great news. Chopper didn't crash.
真失望 我還打算重新嫁人了呢
Shit I assumed and then i remarried.
是嗎 有錢人家嗎 記得你老媽曾經說的：
Oh yeah he rich?
「嫁個有錢人生活有保障 寶貝兒」
What yo momma always said "Just as easy to marry a rich man Felicia honey"
要是每次你提到我媽我能得到一塊錢的話
If I had a nickel for every dumb shit my mom said...
我都已經是個富婆了 順道說一句 你得修好這個烤箱
I wouldn't need a rich man.You gotta fix this by the way.
等我回來就修 別擔心
I'm going to fix it as soon as I get home. Don't worry.
往電腦這邊走走
Hey come closer to the computer.
過來 電腦這邊
Come over to the computer.
讓我看看你的眼睛
Show me those eyes.
你那情況如何
How's everything?
每次都一樣 跟地獄一樣
Same shit. Well from hell.
-準備好了嗎 -預備 3
You ready? - Three.
Two ...
-1 - 現在
- One ... - Go!
這張臉
That face.
憤青！
Sociopath.
代表著專注 決心 濃烈和衝動
That is focus. That is determination. That is intensity. Drive.
- 我贏了 - 討厭你 真討厭
- Hah. - I knew you. I hate it.
- 一會見 -好的 拜拜
- I'll see you soon okay? - Allright. See you.
為什麼動我的東西
Who's touching my shit?
別動我我東西 別動我東西
Dont'touch my shit. Don't touch my shit.
他們想讓我們去下一個工作地點
Can I tell you where to hit on our next location?
卡斯基達
Kaskida.
這些你跟公司的人看過嗎 卡魯扎 維德林 任何人
Was this run by anybody BP? Kaluza. Vidrine anybody?
維德林跟我確認過 這是他們提出來的
Vidrine right about me. He's come from Virginia.
鮑勃 我來告訴你 什麼是最重要的
Bob let me impose upon you what I think is most important here.
我們必須在5月16號之前從馬看多趕到卡斯基達
We need to go to Macondo to Kaskida by 16 May.
卡斯基達不同尋常的大
Kaskida is non-common prospect.
30-40億桶 比公司的產量都大
3 to 4 billion barrels. That worth more than BP itself.
你看我像聖誕老人麼
Do I look like fucking Santa Claus?
你看起來是挺像聖誕老人的
You do look a little like Santa Claus.
邁爾斯為密西根打過球 他確實有路易斯安那的風格
Coach Miles may played in Michigan but that boy got Lousiana soul.
- 對陣薩班嗎 -是的 因為我們贏了
- That's cause we win dummy.
- 好像你上過阿巴瑪大學一樣
Same we like you went to Alabama
又沒跟你說.
Did I ask you
當我還小的時候就有人教我邊招手邊說再見
When I was potty training I was taught to flush way before I see you in Tuscaloosa.
當你是當官的呢?在哪兒開小差
You boys working for the government? Clean the clean room..
我們正在準備最後的泥漿 已經超過35MPa壓力了
We're still clearing mud from our last gig. Over 5000 psi. Grab a mop.
太瘋狂了
That's just crazy..
看看這次丼涌造成的好事
Look at the pressure did to this drill string during the kick.
該好好表揚下啊
That's one for the trophy case.
嘿 帕崔克婸“A有事找我
True that. - Hey Patrick said you got something for me?
是的 先生4天前頁岩分離器4出現故障
Yes sir. Before you all took off last time shaky four goes down
我查了一下 發現了問題的根源
after poking around we finally found the source of the problem.
你看看 我從去年開始就一直幫你留著
Check this out. I've been hiding this for you since your last hitch.
這是顆牙齒
Is that a tooth?
哇哦 我家小姑娘一定會開心死的
Ho buddy you just made my little girl's year.
她爸爸也一樣 謝謝你 我欠你的
And to her old man. Thank you. I owe you man.
好的 現在開始搭建鑽桿
Well let's put together the kelly.
嘿 戈登
Hey Gordon.
嘿 聽了這事你肯定會發瘋的
I'm telling you man it's going to be full-on shift tonight.
他們把斯倫貝謝送回家了
They sent him home.
是的
Yeah.
跟我來 麥克
Walk with me Mike.
- 去幹嗎 - 去謀殺公司某個的頭頭
- Where we headed? - Murder some BP company men.
- 好的 我這有錘子和螺絲刀 -非常好
- Shit I got hammer screwdriver. - Excellent.
麥克 早上你刷牙了嗎
Mike do you brush your teeth this morning?
是的
Yes sir.
- 好孩子 你剔牙了嗎
- Boy did you floss?
沒 為啥
No no why?
剔牙會為你將來省錢省心
Save you a lot of pain and money in the long run I tell you.
- 吉米要去跟公司的某人發火 - 水泥測試沒有做
- Oh shit Jimmy oh we about to go murder BP guys. - They never ran the cement log..
他們啥也沒做
They sent them home and we're doing shit now we going after the BP.
怎麼 欠他們錢嗎
Hey what's the matter? You owe them a lot of money?
來啊 麥克 跟我一起
Come on Mike stay on my hip.
去吧
Get them.
上吧 寶貝
Yeah baby.
看看第51行 你會看到你的預算上限的
Don look at the line 51. You'll see it cost maximum.
沒看到51啊
I do not see 51.
喔 這不是維德林和卡魯扎本人嗎?
Don Vidrine and Bob Kaluza.
- 歡迎 吉米先生 - 是麼?
- Welcome back Mr. Jimmy. - Yeah
現在我們放置了15立方米的水泥
So we got all 500 cc cement poured down?
是的
Yep.
水泥固井是唯一保護我們安全的設施
That cement only thing between us and the blowout.
- 已經凝固了嗎 - 是的
- And it's cued? - Yes.
時間足夠嗎 要做好這件事是需要花時間的
Had enough time huh? Face time doing it right.
如果水泥有問題 那就是問題
I mean that cement job is compromised then everything above it is too.
沒事兒 「休斯敦 我們這沒事兒」
It's not compromised you used to don't have a problem.
我估計斯倫貝斯也是這麼說的
So I assume Schlumberger guy said the same.
而且拉力試驗也是同樣的結果
Cement bond log they ran say the same huh?
我們對水泥的強度是有信心的 是吧
We are confident in the integrity of our cement job are we not?
我們確實對水泥固井的生效很有信心
We're quite comfortable with the integrity of that cement. That's true.
你就像我爺爺一樣
Just like my grandad.
什麼
Pardon.
我爺爺永遠也不去看牙醫
You see my granddaddy he never even went to the dentist.
他不想知道他的牙出了什麼問題.但最後還是得處理它
He didn't want to know what was wrong. Cause then he will have to deal with it.
你不想知道水泥到底是不是有問題
You don't want to know that cement job ran as well as shit
就因為項目已經超期43天 超預算5000萬了
cause you're 43 days and 50 million dollars overbudget.
這就算有結論了吧 吉米先生
You really shouldn't include yourself now Mr. Jimmy.
公司決定開始鑽井 鮑勃 那麼無論結果如何都是你的責任
BP picked this spot to drill Bob.Consequences that's on you guys.
當然 我得處理這個爛攤子 所以我也有責任
Of course I got to try and deal with those consequences. So yeah I'm included the point is
問題是 他們沒做檢驗就讓回去了
You sent the testing team home before they could do their job.
就因為試驗結果可能不讓他們滿意
Maybe give you all some news you all didn't want to hear.
這個試驗得花他們多少錢 12.50萬
What would it cost you right now? The test? 125 grand?
你們公司市值1800億啊 也太小氣了
You're $180 billion dollar company you cheap
我們市值1860億 小氣才能賺更多的錢
That's why we're a $186 billion dollar company We worry about those bills.
我只擔心我的平台
I worry about my rig.
我的人都住在上面 而你們只是租用
My crew lives on it. You just ran it.
丹 我知道我們得停下來做點維護工作
Don. You and I both know we need some downtime for maintenance.
麥克 有多少機器需要檢修了
Mike how many our machines need repair?
- 390 吉米先生 - 390
390 Mr. Jimmy. - Three hundred and ninety? - Yes sir.
是的 差不多是全部機械的10%
Almost all the same to those machinery board.
- 舉幾個例子 -幾個
Name a few for me. - A few?
我想知道有沒有關鍵設備損壞了
I would love to exactly what piece of mission critical equipment are down.
我該從何說起呢
Shit where do I start?
鑽井工作站A BOP控制器
A driller chair process station 18 BOP control part
電話 存儲 GPS天線 監控錄像 互聯網
telephone system pipe rack system GPS antenna direct TV system wireless internet
卷盤 水泵 煙霧報警器 系統混合器 驅動管理 警報系統......
iron roughneck top dryer barrack bag system auxilliary
drivers control saltwater service pump smoke alarm in the galley
為什麼你會覺得熱呢? 因為這堛漯鬚掑]壞了
The reason why you're sweating so hard is because the compressor on the AC is down too.
只有廁所是好的
Everything but the toilet huh?
不是 廁所也壞了 但是那不歸我管
No no you got problem there too but I don't do shitters. That's engineering.
你是幹什麼的?
Who are you?
麥克 威廉姆斯 工程師
Mike Williams Chief Electronic Technician.
我來重複一遍我在直升機上跟那些頭頭們說的話
I'm going to tell you what I told your executives on the chopper ride in
他們來了就走了
At the time...
我們得保證平台的正常穩定
We're gonna properly secure this well for production platform
在他們來采油之前
coming right after us and start pumping oil.
不幸的是 這些工作需要時間
Unfortunately to do it properly takes time.
43天
43 days?
44天
44 days?
繼續數 鮑勃
Keep counting Bob.
45天
45 days?
46天
46 days?
來塊餅乾 鮑勃
Have a cookie Bob.
沒有水泥測試
Can't run a cement log.
我告訴你我們接下來怎麼辦
I'll tell you what we going to do now.
先做負壓力測試 然後再說其他的
We going to run negative pressure test before we do anything else.
如果你真的覺得必要的話
Do you really think we really need to...
我認為這很必要 你也應該這麼想
I really think we need one Bob. So should you.
尤其是我們現在也不知道這口井到底穩不穩定
Especially since we got no idea whether this well stable or not.
接通了！ 好日子要來了！
Hey! Dial tone. Day is looking up.
安德森先生 我是吉米
Mr. Anderson it's Mr. Jimmy.
我們要做負壓力測試 從3000米開始
We're going to run negative pressure test start tripping out 3 000 ft of pipe.
謝謝
Thank you.
43天延誤
Days behind schedule: 43 days.
小伙子 不好意思 我要找麥克 威廉姆斯
Young man. Pardon me. Can you please tell me where I can find Mr. Mike Williams?
是的 在維修站 飯廳隔壁
Yes sir. He is in the ET shops on the second deck by the coffee shop.
- 謝謝 - 午安 先生
- Thank you very much. - Have a good one for the day sir.
你也是
And you sir.
威廉姆斯先生
Mr. Williams?
維德森先生 迷路了
Mr. Vidrine are you lost?
沒
Not at all.
就是來找你聊聊
Just looking to come by and visit with you for a minute.
有什麼我能幫你的麼>
How can I help?
只是感覺會上你還有話要說
Seems as though you had something more you wanted to say in there.
說來我聽聽
I thought I give you the time to say it.
所以這台鑽機壞了
Okay. So this rig is broke?
- 我可沒這樣說 -感覺你就這意思
- I didnt' say that. - Sounds like you did.
維德森先生你來我這到底幹什麼?
Is there a reason why you in my shop Mr. Vidrine?
我們公司是個超大規模的公司 麥克
We a big company Mike. BP.
一個複雜而龐大的組織
Very big complex organization.
有無數的小部件協同工作
A lot of moving parts. Millions moving parts.
有成千上萬的員工
Thousands upon thousands of people.
我們非常努力的試圖保持這些人
And we all work very hard to ensure that all those people.
這些部門都能正常工作 從而得到一個最好的結果
All those movement parts are fuctioning properly as a mean to an ends.
一個可以掙錢的結果
A very profitable win for all of us.
當然了 這是宏偉的目標
They the big picture.
但是也有不一樣的 就像你們這些只看眼前的
They the little picture. Like you and the malfunctioned shitters.
問題在於 所有一切都是相互影響的
Don't you see point of fact they all kind of interconnected.
像流動的水一樣
They flow but working Mike.
如果你這有問題 那一切都有問題
So if you off it's off.
我也有問題 都有問題 整個項目就停了
Then I'm off. Then we off. Then the whole damn train is off.
明白我的意思嗎 威廉姆斯先生
You feel me Mr. Williams?
你吃藥了嗎? 維德森先生
You on medication Mr. Vidrine?
我只是在評估 我們這趟火車
I'm merely trying to assess just how close this train
離脫軌還有多近
is hugging the track.
好吧 我明白
Okay I hear you.
- 想聽我的意見 -恩
You want my take? I mean you really want my take.- I do.
好吧 你這是試圖讓飛機在降落的時候正好用完油
I think you all trying to run out of fuel as the wheels touch down.
那可不是個好主意
Running on gasoline as the plane land is not smart.
這可不是明智之舉 這是一種僥倖
It's flawed thinking. It's hope as a tactic.
記住了 謝謝
Duly noted and much appreciated sir.
這僅僅是個小員工的小意見
Just the opinion of little guy.
那是鯰魚嗎
That a catfish?
恩 65磅
Yeap. 65 pounds.
你們怎麼釣的
What it all caught at? Nibbling?
手抓 直接用手抓魚
Noodling. We noodle for catfish.
有趣的是 我跟我哥們去抓魚的時候
You know that's funny. Cause when we go noodling
我們去到湖上 點上燈
Your best way to fish is the lake. We walk down the boat ramp.
找到最大最黑的洞伸手去掏
We look for the biggest darkest blackest hole we can stick our arm in.
希望這些鯰魚能咬住我們的手
We hope those big son of bitches bite down on us as hard as he can.
這樣我們才能把它抓出來
So we can rip his ass out of that hole
我們希望被咬 被咬才能抓到魚
We want to get bit. That's the plan.
區別在於 我們已經做好被咬的準備了
Difference is we're ready for that bite.
我們有合適的鞋子 帽子 手套 墨鏡 並且做好了一切準備
We are ready. I'm wearing shoes hat gloves golf cap sunglasses and we are ready.
我可不會不做準備的就把手伸進去然後祈求老天保佑
I don't stick my hand with that monster and hope for the best.
沒準備的空想目標是不現實的 丹
Uh huh. Hope ain't a tactic Don.
耽誤你時間了
I thank you for your time.
- 祝你順利 先生 - 你也是
- Have a wonderful day sir. - And you.
卑鄙小人
That some shit.
全體注意
Attention on the rig!
注意 負壓試驗即將開始
Negative pressure test is about to begin.
全體注意
Attention on the rig!
注意 負壓試驗即將開始
Negative pressure test is about to begin.
無關人員請離開現場
All non-essential personnel please stay clear of the rig platform.
順著水流引過來
Bring it to the current.
右轉10° 鎖定176°
Come right two degrees lock in at 176.
右轉10° 轉到176°
Turn right 10 degrees. Change to 176.
轉向中
Turning.
- 戴蒙 這是你的第五杯了吧?
- Damon B. Bankson ... - Is that your fifth cup?
隨便問問
Just saying.
去看看 確認一切準備就緒
Why don't you go ahead and make sure they ready to get after it.
這可能是最終測試了
This might be the final test.
收到
Roger that.
- 又一次負壓測試 -又一次
- Another negative pressure test? - Another negative pressure test.
- 有問題嗎 - 這個井不行
- Is there a problem? - We got a bad well.
油井都這熊樣 幹這行還能指望什麼
They all bad wells. Tough prospect.
抓住這個 好萊塢 進去沒?
- Get this Hollywood? - Have we entered?
就位 鎖定
In position. Locked.
鎖定在176° 船長 -我們向右轉了10°
- Locked at 176 Captain. - Came right 10 degrees.
- 已經準備好做你們的負壓試驗了 - 好
- We locked in you all can run the negative test. - Yeah.
開始吧 傑森
Go head Jason.
收到 關閉上環形防噴器
Lose the annular.
負壓測試開始
Initiate negative pressure test.
開始鑽井管道壓力測試
Initiate drill pipe pressure test.
你真覺得這是最後一次測試了嗎
You really think this is the last test?
該死的 我當然想 這口井來自地獄啊
Shit I hope so yes. This is the Well from Hell girl.
應該不會持續多久吧
Yeah that ain't going to last long.
就這點能耐
That's all you got.
進球了！
Goal!
100磅/平方英尺
100 pounds per squre inch.
問題不大 往回推了點 就是不想讓我們好過
Okay pushing back on us a little. It's trying to keep us on it.
丹 你拿到上個月我給你那瓶酒了嗎
Don you get that bottle of wine that I sent you a month ago?
恩 謝謝我不光拿到了我已經喝過了
I did I did thank you very much. Not only I got it I drank me.
- 不錯吧 - 非常感謝
- Pretty good huh? - Very nice.
那是瓶托斯卡納 對不
It's Super Tuscan yeah?
軋佳 是吧 我知道你會喜歡
Gaya right? I know you like it.
軋亞
什麼
Sorry?
軋亞 這麼叫的
Gaja. So it called.
我想已經他們跑了一半了吧
I think they're about halfway there.
你都喝多少咖啡了 hank
How much coffee you drinking these days Hank?
船長 我幾個月前就戒咖啡了
Look I gave it up several months ago.
現在只喝綠茶
I drink nothing but green tea now.
再沒有接觸咖啡因 每天做做瑜伽
Stop taking the coffee doing yoga everyday.
堅持兩周了已經
Two weeks now.
每平方英吋450磅
450 psi.
我覺得不太行啊
This don't look good to me.
壓力警報
Pressure! Warning!
900 psi.
搞什麼鬼
What the hell? Dammit.
壓力警報.
Pressure alert.
1395磅
壓力警報
Pressure alert.
穩定在1395了 吉米先生
It only 1395 psi Mr. Jimmy.
壓力挺大啊
That's a lot of pressure.
恩 足夠把你的車劈成兩半了
Yeah. Enough to cut your car in half.
打開上環形防噴器
Open up the annular unit.
好萊塢 打開鑽井管到的閥門
Hollywood open the drill pipe valve.
我們得釋放些壓力
We got to free pressure.
同志們 我得說 試驗的結果不行
Gentlemen I had to say this that is a bad test.
也不一定吧
Not necessarily.
丹 一個好的試驗結果
Don a good test ...
從0開始 保持0 到0結束
Starts zero. Stays at zero. Ends at zero.
謝謝
Thank you.
好吧 有壓力 但是沒有泥漿從管道溢出
So there is pressure but there was no mud.
解釋給我聽聽
Flowing out of that pipe. Now explain that to me.
我承認 是挺奇怪的
That's a confusing result I give you that.
我跟卡扎魯已經討論了無數次關於這些鑽井管到了
Kaluza and I have talked about this drill pipe.
是有些奇怪的地方 他管它叫膀胱效應
There's something off with it. He says it's a bladder effect.
膀胱效應
Bladder effect?
恩 傑森應該知道是什麼意思
Bladder effect. He said Jason would know what he's talking about.
壓力表沒有顯示溢出
I say that flow right there.
是的
Right.
看這邊
Look at here.
嘿 別擦我們還有用呢
Hey! We actually needed that.
膀胱效應
Bladder effect.
有一個壓力團
It is a pocket of pressure
阻塞在放噴口附近
trapped around the annular
被傳感器誤讀成鑽井管到壓力
which reeks like drill pressure
因為這些壓力就被阻塞在那
because it is trapped right there
傳感器的附近
sitting right there on the sensor.
如果這個確確實實的壓力問題
If this was a legitimate pressure issue
泥漿應該會從鑽井管到堿y上來
the we would have mud flowing right back
up and out of that drill pipe right there.
我們怎麼驗證這個情況呢
Now how we going to test this?
需要重複一次負壓試驗
We going to run that negative pressure test again.
只是這次在壓井管進行 而不是鑽井管
But we going to run it on the kill line. Not on the drill pipe.
很顯然 鑽井管現在有問題
Obviously our problem is with that drill pipe.
不可能
You cannot have
有如此大的壓力
13 095 pounds of pressure per square inch
大道可以把車劈成兩半
enough to cut your car in half.
還不把泥漿從管道中壓出
and not have any fluid being forced up and out of that pipe by that pressure.
兄弟們 你們鞋上有泥漿嗎 有嗎
Boys do you have a whole mess of drilling mud on your boots out there?
嘿 丹
Hey Don.
堶悼縝b吵的有點火熱
It got hot in the drill shack.
我們有問題 是鑽井管的問題
We have a problem with that drill pipe.
還是傳感器給了錯誤的讀數
or with the sensor giving us a false reading.
還是說 下面千萬個部件都可能有問題了
Or any other of a thousands moving parts down there.
怎麼才能知道呢
Now the way we going to find out
在壓井管上在做一次負壓試驗
is run that negative pressure test on the kill line.
如果壓力是0 吉米先生
and if there is zero pressure Mr. Jimmy
真相也就大白了
Then that is going to tell us all we need to know.
同意
Are we in agreement?
同不同意不知道 不過再做一次試驗也是無關痛癢
I don't know about agreement. Never hurts to run a test.
好滴(?▽︿*)))
Look.
這兒情況如何 Jimmy先生
How we doing here Mr. Jimmy?
不錯 不是嘛 don
We're doing great aren't we Don?
是的是的
Yes we are.
公司的油井
BP's well.
是的
It is.
- 公司的石油 -恩
- Bp's oil. - Indeed.
我們只是來僱傭的工人而已
We just to help you all hire a driller hole.
說得對 吉米先生
You are correct Mr. Jimmy.
但是我們已經延期50天 洞也沒打好
But we 50 days late. And the hole ain't drilling.
吉米先生 廚房有點小問題
Now Mr. Jimmy we have issue in the galley.
一點安全問題 - 不會耽誤你太久
- A whole bunch of people. A safety issue. - It won't take but a minute.
是延遲43天 不是50天 簡單的數學問題
That's are 43 days not 50. Simple mathematics.
既定目標是3月8號 今天4月20號 43天
Where your completion date was March 8. It's 20th April today. 43 days.
恩
Yep.
我還以為你們這些就知道掙錢的油老闆們數學應該不錯
I thought you money greedy sons of bitch at least good at math.
好吧 先生們
Allright gentlemen.
繼續 杜威 在壓井管上進行負壓試驗
Oh hey Dewey. Negative pressure test on the kill line.
轉移到壓井管測試
Switching to kill line test.
開始壓井管壓力測試
Initiating kill line pressure test.
膀胱效應
Bladder effect.
你覺得靠譜嗎
It ran true to you?
雖然丹 維德森這人滿口謊言 不過我覺得還行
Well that came out of Vildrine's mouth that rang true to me. Yeah.
我是說 從原理上看
I mean on it's face yeah.
還是有點道理的 不過呢
There's a logic to it. It's got merit. But
我也說不清楚 對壓井管做壓力測試
I don't apply to kill pipes and kill lines
- 有點太高深了 對我來說 -至少應該看到點泥漿
- A little above my paygrade. - We should've seen some mud.
壓力警報
Pressure alert.
壓井管壓力讀數
好！幹得好！
Yes! Good job!
地平線號將受到公司最高級別的安全表彰
The Deepwater Horizon is receiving BP's highest safety award.
連續7年
for the seventh straight year.
一切都從吉米先生接手開始
And it all starts at the top. The man you call Mr. Jimmy
吉米先生.吉米
Mr. Jimmy Mr. Jimmy.
請致辭
Speech.
保持在0 老闆 測試通過了 沒有殘留壓力
He held at zero boss. Good test. No pressure.
恭喜 通過測試了
Congratulations good test.
鑽井管媮椄O很大的壓力
We still got 14 000 psi on the drill line.
鑽井管和壓井管必須是相等的
Drill line and the kill line should be exactly the same.
應該一模一樣
They should all be lined up.
我們已經知道鑽井管埵麻I問題
We already agreed to test something wrong with the drill line.
為啥還在糾結這個
Why do you keep coming back to it?
我也不知道 這行干太多有經驗了
I don't know. Good old field practice.
沒有泥漿 沒有泥流 我們必須開始了
No mud. No flow. We got to go.
最快什麼時候可以把井準備好
Now how quick can we lock the dough on this well?
通知吉米先生之前我什麼也不會做
I'm not doing nothing until Mr. Jimmy is made aware.
你還是個有主意的成年人麼
Is there a man in you? Is there an adult?
穿的人模狗樣 工作服一套 工作鞋一穿
The dip. The steel toes.
都他媽的扯淡
But it's all bullshit.
壓井管塈馴沒壓力啊
We got zero pressure on the kill line.
膽小如鼠的貨
You nervous as cat.
一點有擔當的決定都不敢做
Afraid to make it work at every turns.
等我回去我就這麼匯報給我上級
That will be my summary back to my bosses in London.
鮑勃
Bob?
同意
Agreed.
行吧 你通知吉米先生吧
Again you can call Mr. Jimmy.
我就不耽誤你們吃冰淇淋了 謝謝
And I no longer keep you from your ice cream for another second. Thanks.
- 我是吉米 - 我做了負壓試驗
- This Mr. Jimmy. - We ended the negative test.
實驗結果沒問題 沒壓力
It was good test. We got no pressure.
準備開始下一步動作了 跟你確認一下
I'm about to start in this place. I want your blessing.
你確定嗎 jason
You sure about this Jason?
壓井管測試正常 我能確定的只有這個
Kill line was good. It was all nothing I'm sure.
他們在催我 我該怎麼做
This guys are all over me. What you want to do?
沒泥流 對不
Zero flow correct?
對 沒泥流
It's correct. No flow.
可以繼續了
Are we good?
好吧 又是慢慢長夜了估計
Well it's looks like it's going to be a long night.
傑森 你先盯著 我半小時過去找你 謝謝
You stay on top of it Jason. I see you on top about half an hour. Thanks.
好吧 兄弟們 測試通過了
Okay guys. Good test.
好耶！
Yahoo.
準備加注10000桶泥漿
Get ready to pull out 10 000 barrels of mud.
夜班開始前我得去沖個澡
I think I'm going to take a shower and wash my day off before I start my night.
- 漫漫長夜 恩 - 去吃點冰淇淋唄 麥克
- It's gonna be long night. - Get some ice cream Mike.
我得保持體形
I'm gonna watch my figure.
我去修幾個煙霧報警器吧要不感覺我要打人了
I'll go fix up some smoke detectors before I'm about to pop somebody in the mouth.
好主意 待我向felicia問好
That's a good idea. Say hi to Felicia for me.
- 吉米先生 -恩
- Mr. Jimmy? - Yes?
拿著
We really need you in this.
- 拍張照 -哦 拍張照
- Just a picture.
吉米先生
Alright Mr. Jimmy.
- 恭喜你 jimmy先生1 - 謝謝兄弟們
Hey appreciate it a lot guys.
你拍了嗎
Did you take the picture?
檢查的怎麼樣了?
Help me check the house.
試驗通過了
We got a good test.
開始轉移泥漿 送到班克斯敦號那邊去
We start sending us some mud. Transfer them to Bankston.
收到
Copy that.
膽小如鼠 老鼠膽子才不小
Nervous as cat. Cat ain't scare.
我以前見過老鼠對著貓唬呢
I had a cat named Oscar used to try to mount my Labrador.
打開環形防噴器
i'm opening the annular.
希望這頭野獸還沒醒
Let's hope that monster ain't awake.
泥漿泵正常工作
Mud pumps are on.
從油井娷鉦儐d漿
Removing heavy mud from well.
存儲到2號泥漿倉
Displacement Holding in Tank 2.
4%
Four percent ...
同志們 測試通過了！
Boys we got a good test.
帥氣！ 加注泥漿吧
Let's pump out all these mud.
搞定了/We're done.
我們就要回家了
We're going home.
班克斯敦號呼叫地平線號
Damon Bankston at Deepwater Horizon.
獲准靠近接收泥漿
You are clear to approach and receive drilling mud.
收到 地平線號靠近接收泥漿
Copy Deepwater. Coming along side to receive heavy mud.
位置參考正常 位置正常 一切就緒
All normal.
主甲板 準備接收泥漿
Master deck prepare prepare to receive the mud.
10000桶
10 000 barrels.
平台上的請注意 我們通過了壓力測試
Attention on the rig. Pressure test was good.
恭喜各位 我們準備離開這個平台了
Congratulations crew. We about to moving on.
這破油井總算完事了
Well from Hell is done boys.
太好了 馬上我就可以登上班克斯敦號回家了
Oh man. The basin soon.
兩天最多三天 在我自己船上
Two or three days maybe. I'll be in my boat.
嘬著啤酒 釣著小魚
Drinking me a beer. Catching us a sucker at the lake.
啊！ 帥氣的泥巴！
Yes! You big beautiful mud.
35%
35%.
太好了 我們要回家了
- Hang on baby. - We are going home!
回家
To home?
我還以為我們計劃出去玩呢
I thought you had plans. I thought you going out.
改時間了
Cancelled.
裹著睡衣 喝點小酒 看看電視
Sweatpants bottle of beer and DVR.
我的最愛
My favorite plan.
簡單的鄉村女孩的生活
Just simple country girl.
55%
55 percent.
75%
75 percent.
- 下一個也這麼操作 -希望也沒啥問題
- Do the same in the next. - Hopefully with fewer problems.
傑森 我這泥流開始變大了
Jason! I got a 20 barrels increased in flow.
- 別 慢下來 - 停止泵泥漿
- Not slowing down. - Alright stop pumping mud.
- 壓力警報 - 不
- Pressure alert. - Oh no.
- 他們把它關了
- Standy. - They're shutting down.
上面一定出了什麼問題
They must not be liking something up there.
我去小解 幫我盯著點
Hey boys. I'm going to take a leak. You guys good?
- 去吧 -好的
- I got you buddy. - All right.
- 壓力警報 - 停不下來
- Pressure alert. - It's not stopping.
讓下面的人都撤- 讓他還有他出去
Clear the drill shack. Get him and him out of here.
怎麼了
What is happening Jim?
哥們 別激動 我們知道會有點問題
Jim what is the excitement. We stipulated there aint something wrong.
我就不該聽你的 趕緊滾出去
I never should've let you push me. Now get your ass out of here before I push back.
我記住你了
That comment will be noted.
準備好回家了
I'm ready to go home.
喝點酒吃個牛排啥的
Drinking beer and eating a steak.
怎麼了
What's going on?
也許不是什麼問題 卡魯先生
Probably nothing Mr. Kaluza.
-小心腳下 -日
- Watch your step over here. - Shit.
你這怎麼了 caleb
What you got Caleb?
他在幹嘛
What is it you do?
糟糕
Shit.
該死的
Dammit.
- 到底怎麼了 - 泥漿溢出來了
- What the hell's going on? - We got flow.
狗日的 不妙啊！
Shit! That ain't good.
傑森 你看到了嗎
Jason you seeing this?
我們這有泥漿
We got flow out here.
-警報 -停不下來
- Warning. - It's not stopping.
傑森 你有看到這個嗎
Jason are you seeing this?
平台上有泥漿！
You got mud on the rig.
他們沒告訴你該怎麼做嗎
Didn't I tell you not to do anything.
只是溢出了一點還是
Is she just kicking or just
- 哦 不 - 離開那兒！
Clear the floor.
該死 傑森
Oh shit .Jason
麥克 怎麼回事? 你那沒事吧
Mike what is that? Is everything okay?
我正在關閉防噴器
i'm closing the annular.
唐 過來這
Duck get in here now.
你把它關了嗎
Are you shutting it in?
沒事了 我把防噴器關了 我們有30秒
Alright we're okay. I closed the annular. We got 30 seconds.
撤離 現在！
Evacuate the floor now!
- 唐 你沒事吧 -恩
- Duck are you okay? - Yes.
把你手指放在緊急脫離系統的按鈕上 準備脫離鑽井管
Get the signal on the EDS. Get ready to cut that pipe.
這！這！
On your way.
阿達姆!
Adam
肖恩!\Shane
我們該怎麼辦
What do we do?
- 卡比爾！ -怎麼辦
- Caleb! - What do we do?
釋放所有管道壓力！
Release the drill pipe pressure!
這 這
Here here.
我懂了 我盡量讓各位滿意
i'm doing my best to accomodate it. But look...
該死的
Dammit!
好了 好了 問題不大 問題不大
Okay. Okay. We're alright. We're alright.
-卡比爾 你沒事吧 - 我們已經關閉管道了嗎?
- Caleb how are we doing buddy? - Did we cut the pipe?
沒事了 防噴器起作用了
We're good. Annular took care of it.
就是個小噴溢
It's just a kick.
我見過最大的「小噴溢」了
It's the biggest damn kick I've ever seen.
她搞定了麥基和她的企鵝
She put a whoop ass on Maggie and her penguin.
別扯了
Get out of here.
真的
She did.
沒用這個搞定了
And she did it all without this?
不是吧！！
No!
貨真價實的恐龍牙齒
That is a genuine dinosaur tooth.
油氣警報 又來了
Gas alarm in the mud pits. Again.
每次都這樣 我取消了
Same one goes off everytime . Off all down.
油氣警報
Alert gas.
我這可以了
Hey Roy!
搞定了 你那呢?
I got it. You got to get out of here.
太遲了
Too late.
壓力警報
Alert pressure.
見鬼 傑森
Shit. Jason!
該死的
Oh shit!
卡比爾 把全部的
Caleb get out of that mud.
防噴器失效了
The BOP ain't working.
我了個去 唐 關閉第二道防噴器
Holy shit. Duck close the second annular.
防噴器故障
Annular failure.
阿達姆 肖恩! 快到泥漿車間來！
Adam! Shane! They Get down to the mud room now.
阿達姆
Adam!
我們得撤了 兄弟
We got to go buddy.
必須撤！
We must go!
得到泥漿車間去 卡貝爾！
We must get to the mud room! Caleb!
-卡貝爾！ -快走！快走！
- Caleb! - Get off the floor! Get off the floor!
二號泵 清空二號泵
It's the Pump 2. Bleed it. Bleed it.
快點
Quick!
卡貝爾 把閥門關閉 引導所有的泥漿到上層管道去
Caleb close the drill pipe behind them.
全部引導開
They blow everything overboard.
傑森 我們該怎麼辦
Jason what do we do?
- 防噴器故障 - rubbie！
- Failure. - We got debris!
- 上帝啊 -見鬼！
- OMG! - Dammit!
caleb 快撤離！
Caleb clear the floor.
你沒事吧
You're alright?
警報沒響 我等你們都撤離
The alarm didn't go off. I'm going to make sure everyone evacuates.
- 快去救生艇 去 -是！
- Get to the lifeboats. Go! - Ok.
哈利 停下來
Halt. Stop.
小心 小心！
Look out. Look out.
什麼情況！
What the hell.
見鬼
Dammit!
耶穌
Jesus.
地平線號 這堿O班克斯敦好 聽到請回答
Deepwater Horizon this is David Bankston. Copy?
防噴器沒有響應
The BOP is not responding.
- 丹羅德 關閉管道 -是
- Duck. Get that button right now. - Okay.
現在！
Right now!
警報！油氣！
Caution. Gas.
唐 唐
Duck! Duck!
發生了什麼
What happened?
凱奇
Keith!
格雷德
Gordie!
加把勁！ 上！
Come on! Get up!
洛伊 加把勁
Roy! You gotta go.
我們必須得走了 必須走！
We gotta go right now.
油氣警報
Alert gas.
糟糕 油氣警報
Shit. The gas alarm.
推進器都過載了
The thrusters are over-revving.
推進器失去控制
I thruster is running away from me.
- 平台位置不能保持 -冷靜
- I'm not going to be able to hold the rig in place. - Calm down.
我的天
OMG.
是我的錯覺還是你那閃了一下了
Is it just me or does it get all bright in there all of the sudden?
紅色 紅色警報！
Magenta. Magenta alarm.
-油井爆炸了 -什麼
- The well is blowing out. - What?
麥克.
Mike.
求救！ 這堿O地平線號 我們
Mayday! This is Deepwater Horizon. We're...
你在幹什麼 我有讓你求救嗎
What the hell are you doing? Did I asked you to call a Mayday!
一會打給你
I call you back! I call you back!
你又分不清是電流不穩還是有爆炸
You don't know the difference between a kick and a goddamn blowout!
- 為什麼屏幕上什麼都沒了
- Why is ? - You don't know shit! Why is the monitor out?
可燃氣體警報
Gas Alert
求救！求救！求救！這堿O地平線號
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday! This is Deepwater Horizon.
堅持住 唐 我來幫你
Come on Duck. I'm going to get you out.
我的天 德威 斯蒂文
Goddammit! Dewey! Steve!
不 見鬼
- No! - Jesus!
求救！求救！求救！這堿O地平線號
Mayday! Mayday!This is Deepwater Horizon.
- 平台起火了 - 發生了巨大的爆炸
- The rig is on fire. - We got a major explosion. We need assistance.
- 你看不到那著火了嗎
- Don't you see it's on fire? - I repeat we have mass casualty explosion.
我們需要幫助
We need assistance immediately.
求救！求救！求救
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday!
求救！求救！求救 這堿O班克斯敦號
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday! This is Damon Bankston.
地平線號起火了
The Deepwater Horizon has exploded and is on fire.
重複 地平線號發生了爆炸並起火了
I say again Deepwater Horizon has exploded and is on fire.
我們看到了巨大的爆炸
We saw a huge explosion.
是的 地平線號著火了
Yes the Deepwater Horizon is on fire.
- 他們都撤離平台了嗎 -沒概念
- Do all left the platform? - We have no idea.
海岸警衛隊
COAST GUARD NEW ORLEARS
這堿O美國海岸警衛隊中心 請講
United States Coast Guard. This is State Command Center and Von Huene speaking.
收到 平台起火
Okay an oil rig on fire. About 48 nautical miles south of Venice.
好的先生 你的船名
Okay yes sir. What vessel are you on? What's the name of your vessel?
海岸警衛隊 這堿Odegan
Coast Guard This is State Command Center. Lieutenant Degan speaking.
平台起火 地點在哪
An oil rig on fire? Sir do you have a position for that?
不確定 我需要你的數據 你的名字
I'm not exactly sure I need to get some information from you first if that's alright.
Can i get your name please?
你的位置
What is your location?
離福爾雄港南160公里
We got a 100 miles south of Port Fourchon.
從服務站得到消息 位置在威利斯南側89公里
48 miles south off the coast of Venice. I have a report from OSV vessel.
經緯度 地點確認了
That lat and long. That's a confirmed position.
先生 我們有衛星圖像了 這
Sir we got a satellite images of the scene. Right here.
我的天
Oh my God.
這事最高優先級
Listen guys we need to bump this up okay.
看看那片海域我們有多少船在
Call land area see what kind of flip cutters we have in the area and
讓他們都過去
divert them over to the area.
看看還有多少飛機可以用
air stations. How many aircrafts do we have left?
-先這樣 -好的
Okay get them going.
見鬼
Shit.
開始撤離！這不是演習！
Evacuation procedure in effect. This is not a drill.
緊急撤離消息 這不是演習
Evacuation procedure is in effect. This is not a drill.
道戈
Dougie?
道戈 能聽到我嗎
Dougie. Hey Dougie can you hear me?
什麼
What?
聽到我說話嗎 dougie
Can you hear me Dougie?
我的小兄弟
My little brother.
什麼
What?
我兄弟生日
It's his birthday. My brother.
你兄弟不在這
Your brother is not here.
你腿能動嗎
What about your legs huh? Can you move them.
我的小兄弟
My little brother.
聽著 道戈 使點勁
Look at me Dougie you gonna need to use them.
我們必須得到救生艇去
We got to get to lifeboat. I'm gonna get you out.
好！
Alright.
見鬼 沒事
Shit. All right.
上面 上面！
Up.
小心點
Carefully.
2號推進器失效
Failure of Propellant 2.
我損失了4台發動機 還有四台可用
I just lost fourth thruster on the fourth side. I only have four left Captain.
怎麼辦
What do we do?
- 我們需要個損失匯報 - 我手動控制
- We need a damage report. - I'm gonna take manual control for the rig.
這堿O庫赫塔 我需要個損失匯報
- 拜託 -救火隊！
- Please. - Fire team now!
班克斯敦號向海岸警衛隊請求救援
We Bankston to the Coast Guard.
地平線號發生了事故
There is an incident on the Deepwater Horizon.
90°右舵 救生衣不是已經再水堣F
We're on 90 degrees starboard. Tell me that lifeboat is on water.
快！我們需要急救工具
Let's go you got the first kits
氧氣瓶
And oxygen tanks?
清空這 快點！
Empty out the supply house. Let's go.
請前往你指定的救生艇
Proceed to assigned lifeboat.
該死的
Son of a bitch!
聽著 我們得上救生艇
Hey! Hey! He needs to get on the boat!
很痛 他傷的很重
He's hurt. He's hurt bad.
我不管！
I don't give a shit!
難道我不想上船嗎
Give him the boat.
看著我 這個人傷的很重 明白不
Listen to me he's hurt real bad. Do you understand me?
冷靜點
Calm down.
你看到吉米先生了嗎
Anybody seen Mr. Jimmy?
我看到他在寢室
I saw him in the accomodation.
我去找吉米 把這個人帶下平台
I'm going back for Mr. Jimmy. Make sure this man gets off this rig.
都冷靜點 冷靜
Okay buddy. Calm down. Slow it down. Move it out.
- 好 -好的 來吧
- Yeah. - Okay let's go.
有人麼?
Hello?
聽到了！你沒事吧
Hey! Hey! Hey! You're good?
- 我想是的 - 你這是去哪
- I think so. - Where are you going?
我也不知道 去匯合點
I dont know. Master.
- 別 去找救生艇 -好的
- You gotta go to the lifeboat okay? - Yeah.
這邊 在左邊
Lifeboat. Right now.
靠著牆 靠著牆
Stay to the wall. Hey! Stay to the wall.
好的
Good.
有人嗎?
Hello?
吉米先生
Mr. Jimmy?
有人嗎
Anyone there?
有人嗎?
Hello!
- 救命！ -吉米！
- Help! - Mr. Jimmy!
有人嗎?
Hey!
誰在那
Who's there?
這邊！
Here quick!
吉米先生 吉米
Mr. Jimmy? Mr. Jimmy?
麥克!
Mike!
我啥也看不見了 發生了什麼事
I can't see shit. I got. What happened?
- 平台爆炸了 - 不
- We blew out Mr. Jimmy. - Oh no.
還在不停的發生小爆炸 到處都起火了
There's secondary explosions. It's on fire everywhere.
我們脫離鑽井管了嗎 井口關閉了嗎
We disconnect it? We cut the pipe.
不清楚 我覺得沒有
I don't know. I don't think so.
必須脫離 麥克 扶我去艦橋
We need to disconnect Mike. Help me get to the bridge.
去艦橋
I'll take you to the bridge.
我會幫你的 來吧
I got you. Alright. Come on.
這是哪
Where are we?
就是你能看到也認不出來
I wouldn't recognize where are we unless we can see it.
- 這根管會爆掉的 - 警報
This pipe is gonna break.
來吧 吉米 快點 吉米
Come on Mr. Jimmy. Come on.
如果掉到水 記得用閃光和哨子
If you find yourself in the water you got a light and a whistle.
明白
You understand?
如果有原油或者其他洩露 遠離平台
If you get into an oil anything swim away from the rig.
我們是等著海岸警衛隊來接我們還是
Should we wait for the coastguard?
不 我們必須撤 走！
No way. We need to go. Come on. Let's go.
- 出發 - 水面都起火了
- Let's go now. - The water's on fire.
- 誰在調度空中資源 - ATC
- Who's coordinating the air assets out there? - ATC. Fixed wing. They have gear.
東區醫院 西區傑弗森都準備好
West Jefferson and East Jefferson and Tulane are prepared to take...
已啟動
Start.
引擎恢復動力
Engine power.
警衛隊1號直升機報告
Coast Guard 1 clear.
有人開始往水婺鶪F 他看到3個人跳了
There are people jumping into the water. He sees 3 people jumping into the water.
- 有人跳了 你聽到了 - 有人跳海
- Jumper. Do you getting this? - They are jumpers?
第一架直升機大概什麼時間到
What's the ETA on the first helicopter.
差不多35分鐘
Sir it's going to be 35 minutes.
太遲了
Let's hope it's not 30 minutes too late.
這堿O海岸警衛隊 b17..
US Coast Guard B17 departing
出發相應地平線號發出的求救信號
on a route to emergency distress call Deepwater Horizon.
預計25分鐘到達目標保持無線電靜默直到抵達
ETA to location in 25 minutes.
進來 進來！
Get in! Get in!
加把勁 沒事吧
Come on. You good?
- 沒事 -好 我們繼續
- Yeah. - Come on.
救命！
Help!
你聽到了嗎
Can you hear?
該死
Shit!
大點聲
Shouts!
誰在那 我是卡貝爾 需要幫忙
Someone there? This is Caleb. I need help in here.
我是維姆
It's Wyman!
我們必須離開這堥麭B都是火警
We gotta get out of here. There's methane everywhere.
我找到他的時候就這樣 傷的很重但是我動不了他
I found him like this. He hurt real bad now. He ain't getting up.
- 別看 - 別 別
- Don't look down alright? - No no.
等一下 該死 你的骨頭卡在縫隙堣F
Wait! Shit His bone caught on the metal.
該死的
Dammit!
麥克
Mike!
嘿 我們得想想辦法 找點啥工具把它撬開
Come we gotta work this. We gotta find something to get it open.
拉！拉！
Pull! Pull!
繼續拉！
Keep pulling!
沒電了
I lost power.
先別動 給我點時間讓我想想
Stop. Just stop a second. Let me think.
我要脫離那些管道
I want to cut the pipe.
嘿！ 安德莉亞 回到你座位上
Hey Andrea get your ass back on station.
我們做不了這個決定
We don't have the authority.
得把油井封閉了
I'm going to seal the well.
別按那個按鈕！
Do not touch that button!
我們必須啟動緊急脫離程序
We need to take the EDS.
我們做不了這個決定！
We don't have the authority.
別按哦
You ain't pushing it.
有人能幫幫忙嗎 求你了
Can somebody help me?
離開這！
Go! Get out of here.
腿斷了也得把你拽出來
You're coming with or without that leg.
保持住 保持住
Hold on. Hold on.
嘿 看著我
Hey look at me.
會疼的你媽媽都不認識你 要忍住！
This gonna hurt like a bitch. You stay calm for a second okay.
看著我 別看下面 看著我
Look at me. Don't look down look at me.
有我們在
We got you.
保持住！
Hold on.
拉 拉
Pull. Pull.
維姆 你還能動嗎
Wyman can you move?
我們走！
Let's go.
帶我去艦橋 麥克
Okay take me to the bridge Mike.
海岸警衛隊 這是degan
Coast Guard. This is Command Center. Lieutenant Degan speaking.
你好
Hi sir.
我不想打擾您 一切肯定都在按部就班
Huh I just huh. I don't mean to bother you. I'm sure everything are just fine.
但是我老公 麥克 威廉姆斯 他在地平線號上
but my husband. Mike Williams is on the Deepwater Horizon and uh
是的 女士 我們接到通知平台上發生了火災事故 目前為止我也就知道這些
Yes ma'am. Right now we only have a couple of confirmed reports with a fire on an oil rig. That's all I can say.
平台上起火了
They're on the Deepwater Horizon?
那麼多平台在那 你確定嗎
Because there's so many rigs out there. You sure?
是的 深水地平線號上發生了火災
Yes there is a fire on the Deepwater Horizon.
目前只有這些信息 不好意思 我得掛電話了
That's all I can say to you Ma'am. Sorry. I really have to go.
發生了什麼
What happened?
- 肯 沒事吧 - 那座塔會砸到我們的！
- Ken you alright? - The derrick is gonna fall on us!
船要走了！
Damn the boat slipped.
我的起重機會毀掉那座塔的
My crane is gonna take the goddamn derrick out.
- 下來 - 快上船！
- It's coming down! - Get on the boat now!
我得把它停下 否則我們都得死
I must stop it or it's gonna kill us all.
嘿 戴爾
Go Dale!
快 快
Go! Go! Go!
幫他上去
Help him up the stairs.
該死
Shit!
你行的 dale
Go Dale!
好樣的 dale
Dale get out!
趕緊出來！立刻！
Get out of there! Now!
上帝啊
Oh my God.
- 艦橋上都有誰在 -Fleytas
- Who's on the bridge? - Fleytas.
庫赫塔
Kuchta.
我們走吧 船已經滿了 我們出發
Let's move on! It is full! Let's move on!
去第一個匯合點
They Go to the meeting point one!
滾上救生艇吧你
Get your ass on the lifeboat.
安德莉亞 庫赫塔 管道脫離了嗎
Andrea Kuchta did disconnected it?
沒有
No.
安德莉亞 把我的手放到緊急脫離系統上
Andrea get my hands on the EDS.
我來切斷管道 封閉油井
I'm gonna cut the pipe and seal this well.
得把火的源頭切斷
We gonna choke this fire.
- 這兒 - 上面一點
- Right here. - No no up up!
上帝保佑
It works.
還在燒嗎
Still burning?
- 石油還在噴出 jimmy先生 - 千萬別啊 別！
- It still flow Mr. Jimmy. - Oh come on. Please! Please!
還是在燒 我們得撤了
It still burning Mr. Jimmy. We gotta go.
- 1號艇最後一位 - 來吧 don 我們上********************
Hey! Hey! Couple more.*********************
嘿 滾遠點 我們先來的
Hey! Hey! Couple more.
上去
Get in!
我們得回復這堛滌吨O
We need to restore power.
- 得讓備用發電機上線工作 - 為了救火
- We need to press the standby generator online. - The fire fighting pump?
不是 我們得盡量保持平台的位置 否則管道會被扯斷的
No we just want to keep this rig on station as long as we can. So that pipe doesn't break.
- 我們也只能做這些了 平台是廢了 - 好吧 試試總沒錯
- That's all we can do. We can't save this rig. - It can't hurt to go try.
好吧 麥克 它在塔台的另外一邊
Thank you very much Mike. It's on the other side of that derrick.
我知道
I know. I know.
- 我跟你一起 - 啥
- I'm coming with you. - What?
- 我跟你一起去 - 你確定
- I'm with you. - You sure?
- 我陪著你 -去吧 麥克
- I'm with you. - Go on Mike.
走吧
Come on.
Natalie this is Felicia Williams.
那座平台仍在火災中 還有東西在燃燒
To our knowledge the platform is on fire. Something is on fire there.
汽油、天然氣或者是原油 是這個意思嗎 麥克
Gasoline natural gas or oil. That understand Mike?
確實
Keep in flames.
- 你好 -提那 我是費莉娜 威廉姆斯
Natalie this is Felicia Williams.
我們的老公在地平線號上一起工作
Our husbands work on the Deepwater Horizon together.
我給海岸警衛隊打電話確認平台上起火了
I just called the Coast Guard and they can just confirmed that there is a fire ...
我想知道你有啥新消息嗎
but I just wondering maybe you heard something.
海岸警衛隊怎麼說
What the Coast Guard said?
就說了有火災
Just that there has been a fire.
謝莉聽說有人從平台上跳到海
Shelly heard there's people jumping off the rig.
你怎麼了
What are you doing?
等會再說 寶貝
Not now babe.
- 出啥事了 -等會兒 寶貝
- What's wrong? - Not now baby.
該死
Shit.
來吧
Come on.
小心點
Easy! Easy!
- 去2號救生艇！
- Lifeboat 4 is full! - Make your way to Lifeboat 2!
- 把救生艇放下去 -我們走！
- Lower the boat! - Go!
見鬼！
Dammit!
見鬼
Alright Alright
該死 該死
Shit! Shit!
- 你帶手套了嗎 -恩！
- You got gloves? - Yes!
進來 進來！
Come in come in!
過來！
Come here!
-麥克 -該死
- Mike? - Shit.
麥克 你在那嗎
Mike are you there?
麥克 恢復動力啊
Mike? Bring the power.
你知道這玩意咋操作嗎
You know your way around this thing?
不 能難到哪去呢
How hard can it be?
來 讀給我聽
Come here. Read this shit off to me.
你他媽扯淡吧
You gotta be shitting me.
- 快點！ -好吧 「從遠程模式切換到『本地』」
- Come on - All right. "Turn the remote switch to 'local' '.
「轉動動力開關到『開』」
"Switching power switch."
好的
"Turn rudder on position."
「按下主啟動開關」 紅色的 就在那
"Press the main start button"
- Red one right there.
你真牛逼啊 竟然能看懂
I'm impress man. I don't know roughnecks can read.
哈-哈-哈-
Very funny.
你知道我有UT architecture的全獎麼
You know I had a full ride to UT architecture school.
- 那你在這幹嘛 - 沒聽媽媽的話
- What the hell you doing here? - I should've listen to my mom.
確實
You should've.
- 吉米 你們那有動力了嗎 - 應該可以了
- Mr. Jimmy you get any power up there? - This should be it
可以了嗎
Do you have the power?
- 我們仍在指定工作區域以外 - 是的
- We still outside the walk circle?- Yes. For outstation.
- 慢慢把我們開回去 -好的
- Turn it slow. - Okay.
慢慢滴
Bring us back slow.
加把勁！
Come on baby! Come one!
- 該死的！
Shit!
天殺的！
「啟動按鈕在「開啟」狀態」
"Get your start key turn on."
抓住你了 抓住你了
We got you! We got you!
注意你的腿
Watch your leg!
「等那個指示燈」
"Wait for the pull plug"
加油啊！
Come on.
應該可以了
This should be it.
好了 好了
There you go.
吉米 你那動力恢復了嗎
Mr. Jimmy did you get power up there?
- 恢復動力 麥克- 別 別
- We have power Mike. - Please. No no.
庫赫塔 能搭把手嗎
Kuchta can you help me?
關門！ 別！別！
Close the door! Now!
- 去救生艇吧 麥克 結束了 - 該死
- Get to the lifeboat Mike. It's over. - Shit!
我們得撤了
Jimmy we have to go.
繼續 繼續！
Let's move on! Let's move on!
小心！
Look out!
都塌了
It's all coming down.
我們得去救生艇那邊
We gotta get to the boat.
關門 我們已經滿員了
- Come on lower the boat. - Shut the door
繼續
Let's go!
加油
Come on.
他們棄我們而去了 跑了！
They left us. They left us!
見鬼！
Shit!
- 緊急救生筏！ - 有人帶刀了嗎
- The emergency liferack! - Somebody got a knife?
需要把刀！
I need a knife!
我有 小心點
I got it. Watch out!
打開它 把它放出去
Open it up!
- 保持方向！ - 轉動吊機！
Open the shaft.
日 快！
Shit come one! Hold the flag!
我們得把他送出去
Come on we got to spin it out !
使勁轉！
Crank it!
盡全力了已經！
The spinning it as fast as I can!
跟我一起 加油
Come on stay with me man. Come on!
狗日的
Shit.
拉緊 拉緊
Tie it up! Tie it up!
該死
Shit!
拉開
Tie it up!
快啊
Come on come one bring it in!
受傷的先上 我們走！
Injured first! Come on!
安德莉亞呢
Where is Andrea?
安德莉亞 我們走！
Andrea let's go!
- 快 安德莉亞
- Come on Andrea!
別 等一下！
No wait! Wait!
火太多了 我們不能從這跳
There is too much fire. We can't jump from here.
我們得爬高點
We need to get up higher.
我們得去高處 走吧
We need to get up higher. Come on.
慢點
Slow down. Slow down.
是救生筏
It's a raft!
堅持住！
Hang on.
加把勁
Come on.
班克斯敦救援隊
Bankston Rescue!
這邊 我們在這
Here! Over here!
找到你們了 來吧
We got you. Here you go.
速度！我們得爬上去 快！
Come on. We got to get up. Come on.
梯子上有人往上爬！
On the stairs going up!
見鬼 快！
Shit! Shit!
快 快！
Come on! Come on!
嘿
Hey.
加油
Come on.
是原版的v8引擎還是新一代的
Original V8 or crate motor?
你的野馬 原版還是新一代的v8引擎
Your Mustang. Original V8 or crate motor?
原版的
It's original.
不錯啊 可能我們得把它重造一遍
It's cool. We might need to rebuild that.
我們 誰
Who's we?
你看還有其他人嗎
Do you see anyone else here?
我和你
Me and you.
聽我說 看著我！
Listen to me. Look at me!
我們爬到這就是為了跳得遠
We up higher we can jump up farther.
明白 我們要越過那些火
Okay? We gonna jump over the fire.
不 不
No no.
我不行
I can not.
你不行啥 重造引擎
Can't what? Rebuild an engine?
跳
Jump.
- 相信我 我們不會落入火中的 - 我還不想死
Trust me we not gonna hit the fire. You hear me?
- 不會死的 看著我 -我不想死
不想死
Our choice right now.
我們的選擇很簡單 要麼跳下去要麼燒死！
is to burn or jump!
不 放開我！
Will you let go off me.
別碰我 別碰我！
Do not touch me! Do not touch me!
- 你跳你的 - 你知道麼
- Jump you! - It's okay.
隨便你
Do what you want.
你知道麼 你做啥我做啥 陪著你
You know what? I'm gonna do whatever you do.
不
No.
- 我老婆 我女兒 都等著我回去 - 別都賴我身上
- My wife is Felicia. My daughter Sydney. - Don't put that on me.
我一定回去跟她們重逢的 你的明白 ！
And I will see them again. Do you understand me?
不跟我一起跳的話 你覺得還有多少幾率可以生還
What are the odds of you getting out of this alive if you don't jump with me right now?
我要離開這個平台 你明白嗎
We're getting off this rig. Do you hear me?
你想待在這 待吧
You want to stay here? You stay here.
嘿 你的野馬啥顏色
Hey what color is the Mustang?
來吧
Come on!
安德莉亞 安德莉亞！
Andrew! Andrew!
聽到名字的答應一聲！
If you hear your name holler out.
安貝爾 肖恩
Albers Shane!
這兒
This!
好萊塢 卡貝爾
Holloway Caleb!
這兒
Here.
安德森 傑森
Anderson Jason!
安德森 傑森 你在這媔
Jason Anderson are you here?
這埵陰q鑽井車間出來的嗎
Is there anybody here from the drill shack?
一個都沒
Nobody?
丹 克拉克 在嗎
Donald Clark are you here?
Dewey Revette?
Shane Roshto?
Adam manner?
Roy Kemp?
上面有醫生
There is a doctor above.
Dale Burkeen?
Gordon Jones?
Karl Inger Klepp?
Stephen Curtis?
Keith manuel.
謝謝你
Thank you.
你沒事吧
You're good?
都下跪
All knees.
--一段禱告 不翻了--
Our Father who art in Heaven.
Hallowed be thy name. Let thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done on Earth as it is in Heaven.
Give us today our daily bread.
Forgive us our trespasses as we forgive those who trespass against us.
--禱告結束--
Lead us not into temptation but deliver us from evil.
你的名字 先生
What is your name sir?
麥克 威廉姆斯
Mike Williams.
先去歇會 然後來找我聊聊
You need to take some rest and after you done you talk to me.
嘿 你在那個平台上
Hey! Hey! You on the rig?
- 是的 - 我兒子離開平台了嗎
- Yes sir. - My son did he get off the rig with you?
- 什麼 -他離開平台了嗎
- Rig? - Did he get off the rig?
我也不清楚
I don't know if he made it.
我兒子呢
Where is my son?
- 為什麼你能回來 -我不知道
- Did he get off the rig? - I don't know.
我兒子 你認識嗎
My son. Do you know him
跟你一起下來了嗎
Did he leave with you?
最好找負責的告訴我點什麼情況
Somebody better tell me something.
有人幫幫忙嗎
Somebody help me.
發生了警報
Actuates an alarm.
你有聽到這些警報嗎
Did you hear any of the alarms?
寶貝 沒事的
My love everything is fine.
麥克 威廉姆斯再也沒有回到海上工作 他和他的家人現在在德州生活
Mike Williams never returned to the sea. He lives with his family in Texas.
我記得我閉上眼睛禱告 希望上帝告訴我妻兒
I remember I closed my eyes and saying a prayer. Asking God ...
我已經盡力了
to tell my wife and my little girl that daddy did everything he could.
如果我能活著出來 肯定是有原因的
And if I survive this it's for a reason.
請舉起您的右手
Please raise your right hand.
你承諾你所述的都是事實嘛
Do you solemnly swear that the testimony you about to give is the truth.
全是事實 只有真相
The whole truth and nothing but the truth. So help you God.
- 是的 - 謝謝
- Yes sir. - Thank you sir.
我們順著光線找過去 救出了
We went to the next light that we saw in the water and retrieve that person.
安德莉亞 我的DP操作員（DPO）
Andrea the dynamic position operator.
安德莉亞 目前生活在加州 不在石油行業工作了
Andrea Fleytas lives in California. She no longer works in the oil industry
我去發佈了最後的警報 我們要棄船了
I went to the PA made the last announcement and said that we were abandoning the rig..
在你看來 平台上是誰負責
Who in your view was in charge of the rig?
- 平台管理員 - 就是說harrell先生
- The OIM. - That would be Mr. Harrell. Is that correct?
是的
Right.
吉米仍在深海平台工作
Jimmy Harrell still working for Transocean
發生了巨大的爆炸
There was a major explosion ...
然後爆炸了第二次
followed by second explosion.
爆炸以後 我呼叫了鑽井車間 沒人應答
After the explosion I called the rig floor. There was no answer.
BP的監理robert kaluza和donald vidrine
BP supervisors. Robert Kaluza and Donald Vidrine
被起訴過失殺人
They were convicted of manslaughter
2015年 這些起訴被撤銷了
In 2015 these charges were dismissed.
那些他們說絕不會發生的事情
Everything they told us could never happen ...
發生了
It happened.
大多數人失去了性命
Men lost their lives.
2010年4月20日 深水地平線號上死了11人
11 men died aboard the Deepwater Horizon of April 20 2010.
爆炸後的燃燒持續了87天 向墨西哥灣洩漏了大約
The blowout lasted 87 days and spilled an estimated
2億1千萬加侖的石油
210 million gallons of oil into the Gulf of Mexico.
美國歷史上最嚴重的采油事故
It was the worst oil disaster in US history
深海浩劫
DEEP HORIZON
Deepwater Horizon (2016)